How do you remember previous parts of the conversation?
你是如何记住以前的谈话内容的？
When you interact with these models, naturally they don't remember what you say before or any of the previous conversation,
当你与这些模型互动时，他们自然不记得你之前说过什么，也不记得之前的任何对话、
which is an issue when you're building some applications like Chatbot and you want to have a conversation with them.
这是一个问题，当你建立一些应用程序，如聊天机器人，你想与他们进行对话。
And so in this section, we'll cover memory, which is basically how do you remember previous parts of the conversation
因此，在这一节中，我们将涉及记忆，也就是基本上你如何记住以前的对话部分
and feed that into the language model so that they can have this conversational flow as you're interacting with them.
并将其反馈到语言模型中，这样他们就可以在你与他们互动时有这种对话流程。
So LangChain offers multiple sophisticated options for managing these memories.
所以LangChain为管理这些记忆提供了多种复杂的选择。
Let's jump in and take a look.
让我们跳进去看一看。
So let me start off by importing my OpenAI API key.
因此，让我从导入我的OpenAI API密钥开始。
And then let me import a few tools that I'll need.
然后让我导入一些我需要的工具。
Let's use as the motivating example for memory, using LangChain to manage a chat or a chatbot conversation.
让我们把使用LangChain来管理聊天或聊天机器人对话作为记忆的激励例子。
So to do that, I'm going to set the LLM as a chat interface of OpenAI with temperature equals zero.
因此，为了做到这一点，我将把LLM设置为OpenAI的一个聊天界面，温度等于零。
And I'm going to use the memory as a conversation buffer memory.
而我要用这个内存作为对话缓冲内存。
And you'll see later what this means.
稍后你会看到这意味着什么。
And I'm going to build a conversation chain.
而我要建立一个对话链。
Again, later in this short course, Harrison will dive much more deeply into what exactly is a chain in LangChain.
同样，在本短课程的后面，Harrison将更深入地探讨LangChain中的链到底是什么。
So don't worry too much about the details of the syntax for now.
所以暂时不要太担心语法的细节问题。
But this builds an LLM.
但这建立了一个法律硕士。
And if I start to have a conversation, conversation.predict, give the input.
而如果我开始进行对话，对话.预测，给予输入。
Hi, my name is Andrew.
嗨，我的名字是安德鲁。
Let's see what it says.
让我们看看它是怎么说的。
Hello, Andrew. It's nice to meet you. Right. And so on.
你好，安德鲁。很高兴见到你。对。等等。
And then let's say I ask it, what is one plus one?
然后我们说我问它，什么是一加一？
One plus one is two. And then I'll ask it again.
一加一就是二。然后我再问一遍。
You know, what's my name?
你知道，我叫什么名字？
Your name is Andrew, as you mentioned earlier.
你的名字是安德鲁，正如你之前提到的。
There's a lot of trace of sarcasm there. Not sure.
那里有很多讽刺的痕迹。不确定。
And so if you want, you can change this verbose variable to true to see what LangChain is actually doing.
因此，如果你愿意，你可以把这个verbose变量改为true，看看LangChain到底在做什么。
When you run predict, hi, my name is Andrew.
当你运行预测，嗨，我的名字是安德鲁。
This is the prompt that LangChain is generating.
这是LangChain正在生成的提示。
It says the following is a friendly conversation between a human and an AI.
它说以下是人类和人工智能之间的友好对话。
The AI is talkative and so on.
人工智能很健谈，等等。
So this is a prompt that LangChain has generated to have the system have a hopeful and friendly conversation.
所以这是LangChain产生的提示，让系统有一个充满希望和友好的对话。
And it has to save the conversation. And here's the response.
而且必须要挽救这个对话。而这里是回应。
And when you execute this on the second and third parts of the conversations, it keeps the prompt as follows.
而当你在对话的第二和第三部分执行时，会保持如下的提示。
And notice that by the time I'm uttering, what is my name?
并注意到，在我说出，我的名字是什么的时候？
This is the third turn. That's my third input.
这是第三轮。这是我的第三次输入。
It has stored the current conversation as follows.
它已将当前的谈话内容储存如下。
Hi, my name is Andrew. What is one plus one? And so on.
嗨，我的名字是安德鲁。什么是一加一？等等。
And so this memory or this history of the conversation gets longer and longer.
于是这段记忆或这段对话的历史变得越来越长。
In fact, up on top, I had used the memory variable to store the memory.
事实上，在上面，我曾用内存变量来存储内存。
So if I were to print memory.buffer, it has stored the conversation so far.
因此，如果我打印memory.buffer，它已经存储了到目前为止的对话。
You can also print this out, memory.loadMemoryVariables.
你也可以把这个打印出来，memory.loadMemoryVariables。
The curly braces here is actually an empty dictionary.
这里的大括号实际上是一个空的字典。
There's some more advanced features that you can use with a more sophisticated input, but we won't talk about them in this short course.
还有一些更高级的功能，你可以用更复杂的输入法来使用，但我们不会在这个短课程中谈论它们。
So don't worry about why there's empty curly braces here.
所以不要担心为什么这里有空的大括号。
But this is what LangChain has remembered in the memory of the conversation so far.
但这是LangChain在迄今为止的对话记忆中所记住的。
It's just everything that the AI or that the human has said.
这只是人工智能或人类说过的一切。
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code.
我鼓励你暂停该视频并运行该代码。
So the way that LangChain is storing the conversation is with this conversation buffer memory.
因此，LangChain存储对话的方式是用这个对话缓冲存储器。
If I were to use the conversation buffer memory to specify a couple of inputs and outputs,
如果我使用对话缓冲存储器来指定几个输入和输出、
this is how you add new things to the memory if you wish to do so explicitly.
如果你想明确地添加新的东西到内存中，这就是你的方法。
Memory.saveContext says, "Hi, what's up?"
Memory.saveContext说，"嗨，怎么了？"
I know this is not the most exciting conversation, but I wanted to have a short example.
我知道这不是最激动人心的谈话，但我想有一个简短的例子。
And with that, this is what the status of the memory is.
就这样，这就是记忆的现状。
And once again, let me actually show the memory variables.
再一次，让我实际展示一下内存变量。
Now, if you want to add additional data to the memory, you can keep on saving additional context.
现在，如果你想在内存中添加额外的数据，你可以继续保存额外的上下文。
So conversation goes on, not much, just hanging, cool.
所以谈话继续进行，不多，只是挂着，很酷。
And if you print out the memory, there's now more stuff in it.
而如果你把内存打印出来，现在里面有更多的东西。
So when you use a large language model for a chat conversation,
因此，当你使用一个大的语言模型进行聊天对话时、
the large language model itself is actually stateless.
大型语言模型本身实际上是无状态的。
The language model itself does not remember the conversation you've had so far.
语言模型本身并不记得你到目前为止的对话。
And each transaction, each call to the API endpoint is independent.
而每个交易，每个对API端点的调用都是独立的。
And chatbots appear to have memory only because there's usually rapid code
而聊天机器人看起来有记忆，只是因为通常有快速的代码
that provides the full conversation that's been had so far as context to the LLM.
这篇文章提供了迄今为止作为法律硕士背景的全部对话。
And so the memory can store explicitly the terms or the utterances so far,
因此，记忆可以明确地存储到目前为止的术语或话语、
"Hi, my name is Andrew," "Hello, Andrew, it's nice to meet you," and so on.
"你好，我叫安德鲁，""你好，安德鲁，很高兴见到你，"等等。
And this memory storage is used as input or additional context to the LLM
而这个内存存储被用作LLM的输入或附加背景
so that it can generate an output as if it's just having the next conversational turn,
这样它就能产生一个输出，就好像它只是在进行下一个对话回合、
knowing what's been said before.
知道以前说过什么。
And as the conversation becomes long, the amounts of memory needed becomes really, really long.
当对话变得很长时，所需的内存量也变得非常非常长。
And thus, the cost of sending a lot of tokens to the LLM,
因此，向LLM发送大量代币的成本、
which usually charges based on the number of tokens it needs to process,
它通常根据它需要处理的代币数量来收费、
will also become more expensive.
也将变得更加昂贵。
So LLM provides several convenient kinds of memory to store and accumulate the conversation.
所以LLM提供了几种方便的存储器来存储和积累对话。
So far, we've been looking at the conversation buffer memory.
到目前为止，我们一直在看对话缓冲区的内存。
Let's look at a different type of memory.
让我们看一下不同类型的记忆。
I'm going to import the conversation buffer window memory that only keeps a window of memory.
我要导入只保留一个窗口内存的对话缓冲区。
If I set memory to conversational buffer window memory with k=1,
如果我将内存设置为对话缓冲区窗口内存，k=1、
the variable k=1 specifies that I want it to remember just one conversational exchange.
变量k=1表示我希望它只记住一次对话交流。
That is, one utterance from me and one utterance from the chatbot.
也就是说，我说一句话，聊天机器人就说一句话。
So now if I were to have it save context, "Hi, what's up," not much, just hanging.
所以现在如果我让它保存上下文，"嗨，怎么了？"不多，只是挂着。
If I were to look at memory.load variables, it only remembers the most recent utterance.
如果我看一下memory.load的变量，它只记得最近的话语。
Notice it's dropped. "Hi, what's up?"
注意到它被丢弃了。"嗨，怎么了？"
It's just saying, "Human says not much, just hanging," and the AI says "Cool."
它只是说，"人类说的不多，只是挂着"，而人工智能说 "酷"。
So that's because k was equal to 1.
所以这是因为k等于1。
So this is a nice feature because it lets you keep track of just the most recent few conversational turns.
因此，这是一个很好的功能，因为它可以让你只跟踪最近的几个对话回合。
In practice, you probably won't use this with k=1.
在实践中，你可能不会在k=1的情况下使用这个。
You use this with k set to a larger number.
你在使用时，将k设置为一个较大的数字。
But still, this prevents the memory from growing without limit as the conversation goes longer.
但是，这仍然阻止了记忆随着谈话的延长而无限制地增长。
And so if I were to rerun the conversation that we had just now,
因此，如果我重演我们刚才的对话、
we'll say, "Hi, my name is Andrew. What is 1+1?"
我们会说，"嗨，我的名字是安德鲁。什么是1+1？"
And now I ask it, "What is my name?"
现在我问它："我的名字是什么？"
Because k=1, it only remembers the last exchange versus "What is 1+1?"
因为k=1，它只记得最后一次交换与 "1+1是什么？"
The answer is 1+1=2, and it's forgotten this early exchange, which now says,
答案是1+1=2，它忘记了这个早期的交流，现在说、
"Sorry, don't have access to that information."
"对不起，没有机会接触到这些信息。"
One thing I hope you will do is pause the video, change this to true in the code on the left,
我希望你能做的一件事是暂停视频，在左边的代码中把这一点改为真、
and rerun this conversation with verbose=true,
并以verbose=true重新运行这个对话、
and then you will see the prompts actually used to generate this,
然后你会看到实际用于生成这个的提示、
and hopefully you see that the memory, when you're calling the LLM on "What is my name?"
并希望你看到，当你在 "我叫什么名字？"上打电话给法律硕士时，记忆力。
that the memory has dropped this exchange where it learned "What is my name?"
记忆中已经放弃了这种交流，在那里它学会了 "我的名字是什么？"
which is why it now says it doesn't know "What is my name?"
这就是为什么它现在说它不知道 "我的名字是什么？"
With the conversational token buffer memory,
有了对话令牌缓冲存储器、
the memory will limit the number of tokens saved.
存储器将限制保存的代币数量。
And because a lot of LLM pricing is based on tokens,
而且因为很多LLM的定价都是基于代币的、
this maps more directly to the cost of the LLM calls.
这更直接地反映了LLM呼叫的成本。
So if I were to say the max token limit is equal to 50,
因此，如果我说最大的代币限额等于50、
and actually let me inject a few comments.
实际上让我注入一些评论。
So let's say the conversation is, "AI is what? Amazing."
所以我们说对话是："AI是什么？很神奇。"
Back propagation is "What? Beautiful." Chatbot is "What? Charming."
背面传播是 "什么？"美丽。聊天机器人是 "什么？迷人。"
I use ABC as the first letter of all of these conversational terms.
我把ABC作为所有这些对话术语的第一个字母。
We can keep track of what was said when.
我们可以记下什么时候说过什么话。
If I run this with a high token limit,
如果我用高的代币限额来运行这个、
it has almost the whole conversation.
它几乎有整个对话。
If I increase the token limit to 100,
如果我把代币的上限提高到100、
it now has the whole conversation starting with "AI is what?"
现在整个对话都以 "人工智能是什么？"开始。
If I decrease it,
如果我减少它、
then it chops off the earlier parts of this conversation
然后它把这个对话的早期部分砍掉了
to retain the number of tokens corresponding to the most recent exchanges,
以保留最近一次交易所对应的代币数量、
but subject to not exceeding the token limit.
但以不超过代币限额为前提。
In case you're wondering why we needed to specify an LLM,
如果你想知道为什么我们需要指定一个法律硕士、
it's because different LLMs use different ways of counting tokens.
这是因为不同的LLM使用不同的方式来计算tokens。
So this tells it to use the way of counting tokens
因此，这告诉它要使用计数令牌的方式
that the chat OpenAI LLM uses.
聊天的OpenAI LLM使用的是 "A"。
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code,
我鼓励你暂停该视频并运行该代码、
and also try modifying the prompt to see if you can get a different output.
并尝试修改提示，看看是否能得到不同的输出。
Finally, there's one last type of memory I want to illustrate here,
最后，我想在这里说明的是最后一种类型的记忆、
which is the conversation summary buffer memory.
这是对话摘要缓冲区的内存。
And the idea is, instead of limiting the memory
而这个想法是，与其限制内存
to a fixed number of tokens based on the most recent utterances,
语词的固定数量，以最近的语词为基础、
or a fixed number of conversational exchanges,
或固定数量的对话交流、
let's use an LLM to write a summary of the conversation so far,
让我们用一个法律硕士来写一个到目前为止的谈话摘要、
and let that be the memory.
并让这成为记忆。
So here's an example where I'm going to create a long string
因此，这里有一个例子，我将创建一个长字符串
with someone's schedule.
与某人的时间表。
"This meeting at 8am with your product team,
"早上8点和你的产品团队开这个会、
you need your PowerPoint presentation," and so on and so on.
你需要你的PowerPoint演示文稿，"等等，等等。
So this is a long string saying what's your schedule.
所以这是一长串说你的时间表是什么。
Maybe ending with a noon lunch at the Italian restaurant with a customer,
也许以中午在意大利餐厅与顾客共进午餐结束、
bring your laptop, show the latest LLM demo.
带上你的笔记本电脑，展示最新的LLM演示。
And so let me use a conversation summary buffer memory
因此，让我用一个对话摘要缓冲记忆
with a max token limit of 400 in this case,
在这种情况下，最大令牌限制为400、
pretty high token limit,
相当高的代币限额、
and I'm going to insert in a few conversational terms,
而我要在其中插入一些对话性的术语、
in which we start with "Hello," "What's up,"
其中，我们以 "你好"、"你好 "开始。
"No one's just hanging," "Cool,"
"没有人只是挂着。""很酷。"
and then "What is on the schedule today?"
然后是 "今天有什么安排？"
and the response is, you know, "That long schedule."
而回应是，你知道，"那个漫长的时间表"。
So this memory now has quite a lot of text in it.
因此，这段记忆现在有相当多的文字在里面。
In fact, let's take a look at the memory variables.
事实上，让我们看一下内存变量。
It contains that entire piece of text
它包含了那一整片的文字
because 400 tokens was sufficient to store all this text.
因为400个令牌足以存储所有这些文本。
But now, if I were to reduce the max token limit, say to 100 tokens,
但现在，如果我减少最大的代币限制，比如说减少到100个代币、
remember this stores the entire conversational history.
请记住，这储存了整个对话历史。
If I reduce the number of tokens to 100,
如果我把代币的数量减少到100个、
then the conversation summary buffer memory has actually used an LLM,
那么对话摘要缓冲区内存实际上已经使用了一个LLM、
the OpenAI endpoint in this case,
在这种情况下的OpenAI端点、
because that's what we have set the LLM to,
因为这就是我们为LLM设定的目标、
to actually generate a summary of the conversation so far.
来实际生成一个迄今为止的对话摘要。
So the summary is, "Human AI engage in small talk before a certain day's schedule,"
因此，总结起来就是："人类人工智能在某一天的日程安排之前进行小范围的交谈"。
"AI informs human in a morning meeting," blah, blah, blah,
"人工智能在晨会上通知人类，"等等，等等，等等、
"Lunch meeting with customer interested in AI, latest AI developments."
"与对人工智能感兴趣的客户进行午餐会议，最新的人工智能发展。"
And so, if we were to have a conversation using this LLM,
因此，如果我们要用这个法学硕士来进行对话、
then create a conversation chain, same as before,
然后创建一个对话链，和以前一样、
and let's say that we were to ask input,
假设我们要问投入、
"What would be a good demo to show?"
"有什么好的演示可以展示？"
I said verbose equals true, so here's the prompt.
我说过verbose等于true，所以这里有提示。
The LLM thinks the current conversation has had this discussion so far
法学硕士认为目前的谈话到目前为止有这样的讨论
because that's the summary of the conversation.
因为这就是谈话的摘要。
And just one note, if you're familiar with the OpenAI chat API endpoint,
还有一点，如果你熟悉OpenAI的聊天API端点、
there is a specific system message.
有一个特定的系统信息。
In this example, this is not using the official OpenAI system message,
在这个例子中，这不是使用OpenAI的官方系统信息、
it's just including it as part of the prompt here,
它只是把它作为这里的提示的一部分、
but it nonetheless works pretty well.
但它还是很好用。
And given this prompt, the LLM outputs,
而鉴于这种提示，法律硕士的输出、
"Basic conversation in AI developments,"
"人工智能发展中的基本对话"。
"suggests showcasing our latest NLP capabilities."
"建议展示我们最新的NLP能力"。
Okay, that's cool.
好的，这很好。
Well, it's making some suggestions to the cool demos
好吧，它对酷炫的演示提出了一些建议
and makes you think, if I was meeting a customer, I would say,
并让你想到，如果我是在见一个顾客，我会说、
"Boy, if only there were open source framework available
"孩子，如果有开放源码的框架就好了
to help me build cool NLP applications using LLMs."
以帮助我使用LLM建立很酷的NLP应用。"
Good things are launching.
好东西正在启动。
And the interesting thing is,
而有趣的是、
if you now look at what has happened to the memory,
如果你现在看一下记忆发生了什么、
so notice that here it has incorporated the most recent AI system output,
所以请注意，这里它已经纳入了最新的人工智能系统输出、
whereas my utterance, asking it, "Won't be a good demo to show,"
而我的发言，问它："不会是一个很好的演示节目吧。"
has been incorporated into the system message,
已被纳入系统信息、
the overall summary of the conversation so far.
到目前为止，对话的总体总结。
With the conversation summary buffer memory,
有了对话摘要缓冲存储器、
what it tries to do is keep the explicit storage of the messages
它试图做的是保持信息的明确存储
up to the number of tokens we have specified as a limit.
到我们指定的代币数量为限。
So, you know, this part, the explicit storage,
所以，你知道，这部分，明确的存储、
we try to cap at 100 tokens because that's what we asked for.
我们试图将上限定为100个代币，因为这是我们要求的。
And then anything beyond that, it will use the LLM to generate a summary,
然后任何超出这个范围的事情，它都会使用LLM来生成一个摘要、
which is what is seen up here.
这就是在这里看到的情况。
And even though I've illustrated these different memories
尽管我已经说明了这些不同的记忆
using a chat as a running example,
用一个聊天记录作为一个运行的例子、
these memories are useful for other applications too,
这些记忆对其他应用也很有用、
where you might keep on getting new snippets of text
在这里你可能会不断得到新的文本片段
or keep on getting new information,
或不断获得新的信息、
such as if your system repeatedly goes online to search for facts,
例如，如果你的系统反复上网搜索事实、
but you want to keep the total memory used to store this growing list of facts
但你想保持用于存储这个不断增长的事实列表的总内存
as, you know, capped and not growing arbitrarily long.
因为，你知道，有上限，不会任意增长。
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code.
我鼓励你暂停该视频并运行该代码。
In this video, you saw a few types of memory,
在这个视频中，你看到了几种类型的内存、
including buffer memories that limits based on number of conversation exchanges
包括基于对话交流数量限制的缓冲存储器
or tokens, or a memory that can summarize tokens above a certain limit.
或代币，或一个能总结出超过一定限度的代币的存储器。
LangChain actually supports additional memory types as well.
LangChain实际上也支持额外的内存类型。
One of the most powerful is vector data memory.
其中最强大的是矢量数据存储器。
If you're familiar with word embeddings and text embeddings,
如果你熟悉单词嵌入和文本嵌入、
the vector database actually stores such embeddings.
矢量数据库实际上存储了这种嵌入。
If you don't know what that means, don't worry about it.
如果你不知道这意味着什么，就不要担心了。
Harrison will explain it later.
哈里森以后会解释。
And it can then retrieve the most relevant blocks of text
然后，它可以检索到最相关的文本块
using this type of vector database for its memory.
使用这种类型的矢量数据库作为其内存。
And LangChain also supports entity memories,
而LangChain也支持实体记忆、
which is applicable when you want it to remember details about specific people,
这适用于你想让它记住特定人的细节的时候、
specific other entities, such as if you talk about a specific friend,
具体的其他实体，比如说如果你谈论一个具体的朋友、
you can have LangChain remember facts about that friend,
你可以让LangChain记住关于那个朋友的事实、
which would be an entity in an explicit way.
这将是一个实体的明确方式。
When you're implementing applications using LangChain,
当你使用LangChain实现应用程序时、
you can also use multiple types of memories,
你也可以使用多种类型的记忆、
such as using one of the types of conversation memory that you saw in this video,
例如使用你在这段视频中看到的对话记忆类型之一、
plus additionally, entity memory to recall individuals.
另外，实体记忆来回忆个人。
So this way, you can remember maybe a summary of the conversation,
所以这样一来，你就可以记住也许是谈话的摘要、
plus an explicit way of storing important facts about important people in the conversation.
再加上一种明确的方式来存储谈话中重要人物的重要事实。
And of course, in addition to using these memory types,
当然，除了使用这些内存类型之外、
it's also not uncommon for developers to store the entire conversation
开发者将整个对话内容存储起来也是很常见的。
in the conventional database, some sort of key value store or SQL database.
在传统数据库中，某种键值存储或SQL数据库。
So you could refer back to the whole conversation for auditing
因此，你可以参考整个对话来进行审计
or for improving the system further.
或用于进一步改进该系统。
And so that's memory types.
所以这就是记忆类型。
I hope you find this useful building your own applications.
我希望你在建立你自己的应用程序时发现这很有用。
And now let's go on to the next video to learn about the key building block of LangChain,
现在让我们继续看下一个视频，了解LangChain的关键构建块、
namely the chain.
即链条。